

Sunnyvale, CA, United States

About Me

I am currently a Senior Research Engineer/Scientist at InnoPeak Technology (a.k.a. OPPO US Research Center), working on R&D for XR (AR/VR/MR) related projects. Before that, I was a visiting research scholar at Louisiana State University, where I worked with Dr. Jinwei Ye. I received my Ph.D. from ShanghaiTech University, advised by Dr. Jingyi Yu, and received my Bachelor's degree from Shanghai Jiao Tong University. My research interests lie in computer vision, deep learning, computer graphics and computational photography, with a focus on neural rendering, implicit neural representation, and 3D reconstruction.

Education

SCHOOL OF INFORMATION SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, ShanghaiTech University

Shanghai, China

PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sept. 2017 - Jan. 2022

- · Research Areas: Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Computer Graphics, Computational Photography
- Advisor: Dr. Jingyi Yu | Lab

SCHOOL OF INFORMATION SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, ShanghaiTech University

Shanghai, China

Sept. 2014 - Sept. 2017

MASTER IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING (TRANSITION TO PHD) · Research Areas: Integrated Circuit

• Advisor: Dr. Pingqiang Zhou | Lab

UM-SJTU JOINT INSTITUTE, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Shanghai, China

BACHELOR DEGREE IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, MINOR IN ANIMATION

Sept. 2010 - Aug. 2014

Experience _____

InnoPeak Technology (a.k.a. OPPO US Research Center)

Palo Alto, CA

SENIOR RESEARCH ENGINEER

Aug. 2022 - Present

• Develop algorithms and systems for XR (AR/VR/MR) applications.

Louisiana State University

Baton Rouge, LA

VISITING RESEARCH SCHOLAR

Oct. 2021 - Jul. 2022

- Advisor: Dr. Jinwei Ye
- Develop polarimetric imaging algorithms and systems for 3D reconstruction of objects with challenging surface reflectance
- · Develop light field imaging algorithms for 3D reconstruction of underwater objects and fluid flow.

Google

San Francisco, CA (Remote)

RESEARCH INTERN

June 2020 - Dec. 2020

 Develop a multi-resolution implicit neural representation for 3D geometries, supporting numerous tasks including geometry auto-encoding/decoding/interpolation/completion.

Louisiana State University

Baton Rouge, LA

VISITING RESEARCH SCHOLAR

July 2018 - Jan. 2019

- · Advisor: Dr. Jinwei Ye
- · Develop an uncalibrated near-field color photometric stereo algorithm and system for high-fidelity human face reconstruction from single image.

Cadence Shanghai, China

INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July 2016 - Sept. 2016

• Investigate routability-aware routing algorithms to reduce congestion and latency.

Publications

(* denotes equal contribution, † denotes corresponding author)

Conference

[C1] Spacetime Gaussian Feature Splatting for Real-Time Dynamic View Synthesis
Zhan Li, Zhang Chen[†], Zhong Li[†], Yi Xu

CVPR 2024

[project page] [paper] [code]

[C2] NeuRBF: A Neural Fields Representation with Adaptive Radial Basis Functions

Zhang Chen[†], Zhong Li[†], Liangchen Song, Lele Chen, Jingyi Yu, Junsong Yuan, Yi Xu

ICCV 2023 (Oral Presentation)

[project page] [paper] [code]

[C3] Relit-NeuLF: Efficient Relighting and Novel View Synthesis via Neural 4D Light Field

Zhong Li, Liangchen Song, **Zhang Chen**, Xiangyu Du, Lele Chen, Junsong Yuan, Yi Xu

ACM MM 2023

[project page] [paper] [code]

[C4] High Fidelity 3D Hand Shape Reconstruction via Scalable Graph Frequency Decomposition

Tianyu Luan, Yuanhao Zhai, Jingjing Meng, Zhong Li, **Zhang Chen**, Yi Xu, Junsong Yuan

CVPR 2023

[paper]

[C5] Multiresolution Deep Implicit Functions for 3D Shape Representation

Zhang Chen, Yinda Zhang, Kyle Genova, Sean Fanello, Sofien Bouaziz, Christian Häne, Ruofei Du, Cem Keskin, Thomas Funkhouser, Danhang Tang

ICCV 2021

[paper]

[C6] A Neural Rendering Framework for Free-Viewpoint Relighting

Zhang Chen, Anpei Chen, Guli Zhang, Chengyuan Wang, Yu Ji, Kiriakos N. Kutulakos, Jingyi Yu

CVPR 2020

[paper] [code]

[C7] 3D Face Reconstruction Using Color Photometric Stereo with Uncalibrated Near Point Lights

Zhang Chen, Yu Ji, Mingyuan Zhou, Sing Bing Kang, Jingyi Yu

ICCP 2020

[paper]

[C8] An Optical Flow Based Multi-Object Tracking Approach Using Sequential Convex Programming

Qingwen Xu, Zhengpeng He, Zhang Chen, Yuning Jiang

ICARCV 2020

[paper]

[C9] Photo-Realistic Facial Details Synthesis From Single Image

Anpei Chen, Zhang Chen, Guli Zhang, Ziheng Zhang, Kenny Mitchell, Jingyi Yu

ICCV 2019 (Oral Presentation)

[project page] [paper] [code]

[C10] Deep Eyes: Binocular Depth-from-Focus on Focal Stack Pairs

Xinqing Guo*, Zhang Chen*, Siyuan Li, Yang Yang, Jingyi Yu

PRCV 2019 (Oral Presentation)

[paper]

[C11] Sparse Photometric 3D Face Reconstruction Guided by Morphable Models Xuan Cao, Zhang Chen, Anpei Chen, Xin Chen, Shiying Li, Jingyi Yu **CVPR 2018** [paper] [C12] How Secure Is Split Manufacturing in Preventing Hardware Trojan? Zhang Chen, Pingqiang Zhou, Tsung-Yi Ho, Yier Jin AsianHOST 2016 [paper] Journal [J1] Polarimetric Helmholtz Stereopsis Yuqi Ding, Yu Ji, **Zhang Chen**, Mingyuan Zhou, Sing Bing Kang, Jinwei Ye IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI) 2024 [paper] [J2] NeRFPlayer: A Streamable Dynamic Scene Representation with Decomposed Neural Radiance Fields Liangchen Song, Anpei Chen, Zhong Li, Zhang Chen, Lele Chen, Junsong Yuan, Yi Xu, Andreas Geiger IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG) 2023 (Present at IEEE VR 2023) [project page] [paper] [J3] Full-Volume 3D Fluid Flow Reconstruction with Light Field PIV Yuqi Ding, Zhong Li, **Zhang Chen**, Yu Ji, Jingyi Yu, Jinwei Ye IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI) 2023 [project page] [paper] [J4] Light Field-Based Underwater 3D Reconstruction Via Angular Resampling

[J4] Light Field-Based Underwater 3D Reconstruction Via Angular Resampling Yuqi Ding, Zhang Chen, Yu Ji, Jingyi Yu, Jinwei Ye IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging (TCI) 2023 [paper]

[J5] SofGAN: A Portrait Image Generator with Dynamic Styling Anpei Chen*, Ruiyang Liu*, Ling Xie, Zhang Chen, Hao Su, Jingyi Yu ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG) 2022 (Present at SIGGRAPH 2022) [project page] [paper] [code]

[J6] Deep Eyes: Joint Depth Inference Using Monocular and Binocular Cues Zhang Chen*, Xinqing Guo*, Siyuan Li, Yang Yang, Jingyi Yu Neurocomputing 2021 [paper] [data]

[J7] How Secure Is Split Manufacturing in Preventing Hardware Trojan?
Yajun Yang, Zhang Chen, Yuan Liu, Tsung-Yi Ho, Yier Jin, Pingqiang Zhou
ACM Transactions on Design Automation of Electronic Systems (TODAES) 2020
[paper]

Patent

Jingyi Yu, **Zhang Chen**, Anpei Chen, Xin Chen, and Shiying Li. "3D Human Face Reconstruction Method, System, Image Processing System and Storage Medium." CN111696146A. Mar. 14 2019.

Skills

Programming Languages Python, MATLAB, C/C++, LTEX

Python/Machine Learning PyTorch, TensorFlow, MXNet, OpenCV

Platform/Software Linux, Windows, Git, Docker, conda, Agisoft Metashape

Professional Activities

Conference Reviewer

SIGGRAPH (2024); CVPR (2022-2024); ICCV (2023); ECCV (2022, 2024); IEEE VR (2024); ACM MM (2023); 3DV (2022, 2024); IJCAI (2023-2024); WACV (2023-2024)

Journal Reviewer

TPAMI; TIP

Invited Talks

Low-Cost Realistic 3D Face Reconstruction. School of Electrical Engineering & Computer Science, Louisiana State University. September, 2018.

Course Lecturing

Programming Digital Media. School of Electrical Engineering & Computer Science, Louisiana State University. Jan.-May, 2022.

Honors & Awards _

2019 **Best Paper Nomination**, PRCV 2019

2016 National Scholarship, Shanghai Tech University

2016 **Outstanding Student**, ShanghaiTech University

2015 **Outstanding Student**, ShanghaiTech University

2014 **Outstanding Graduate**, Shanghai Jiao Tong University